I have seen ABC today for her pre-operator visit for weight management.
I have explained to her the need for Optifast for weight loss prior to these procedures
to make it safer because of the large size of her liver.
She understands this.
Impression plan. We are going to put her on two weeks of Optifast at around 900 calories. I have also explained the risks and potential complications of laparoscopic colosyctomy to
her in detail including bleeding, infection, deep venous, thrombosis, pulmonary embolism,
injury to the small intestine, stomach, liver, leak from the cystic duct, common bile duct
and possible need for ERCPA and further surgery. This surgery is going to be planned for October 6.
This is for Kolelothiasis prior to her lab banning procedure.
I have also reviewed with her the risks and potential complications of laparoscopic gastric banning including bleeding, infection, deep venous, thrombosis, pulmonary embolism,
including bleeding infection deep venous thrombosis pulmonary embolism slippage of man erosion of the man injury to the esophagus
leakage of the band, erosion of the band, injury to the esophagus, stomach and small
intestine, large intestine, spleen, liver, injury to the band, port or tubing, necessitating
replacement of the band or porting a tubing among other potential complications and
she understands.
We are going to proceed for laparoscopic gastric banning.
I have reviewed her entire chart in detail.
I have also gone over with her the Fairfield Country Bariatric Concern Form for
banding and all the risks.
She has also signed the St. Vincent Hospital Concern Form for lap banding.
She has taken the pre-operative quiz for banding. She has assigned the pre-op and post-op instructions and understands them and we reviewed them.
We have reviewed with her any potential other issues and I have answered her questions.
She has taken the quiz and done fairly well.
She has also planned for surgical intervention.